Register of the Paul Robert Hanna Papers, 1920-1997
Hoover Institution Archives
- PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES, 1900-1983 (Boxes 18-34)
  - Chronological file
    - 1958
      - August 4-15, workshop, "Developing a Rationale for the Selection of Production of Audio-Visual Materials for the Social Studies," California State Department of Education, Donner Summit Lodge, California (Folder 6-8)
      - December 19, conference, Asian Universities on Cultural Cooperation, Manila, Philippines (Folder 9)
    - 1959
      - General (Folder 10)
      - January 24-27, conference, Policies and Strategy for Strengthening the Curriculum of the American Public Schools, Stanford, California (Folder 11)
      - February 14-18, convention, American Assocation of School Administrators, Atlantic City, New Jersey (Folder 12)
      - February 20, speaking engagement, New Trier Township Institute, New Trier, Illinois (Folder 13)
      - February 27-28, testimony, Citizens Advisory Commission of the Joint Interim Committee on the Public Education System, California Legislature, Sacramento, California (Folder 14)
      - March 2, meeting, Department of Elementary School Principals, National Education Association, Los Angeles, California (Folder 15)
      - June 25-27, conference, "Schools for the Future," Miami University, Oxford, Ohio (Folder 16)
      - July 1, speaking engagement, Phi Delta Kappa luncheon, Stanford, California (Folder 17)
      - July 2-25--see SUBJECT FILE, Kellogg Foundation, meetings
      - August 17-28, conference, Fifteenth Administrative and Supervisory Work Conference, Dallas Independent School District, Dallas, Texas (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - September 12-13--see SUBJECT FILE, Kellogg Foundation, meetings
    - 1960
      - General (Folder 2)
      - February----see SUBJECT FILE, Houghton Mifflin Company, Spelling textbook project, promotional materials, miscellaneous campaigns
      - February 13-17, conference, American Assocation of School Administrators, Atlantic City, New Jersey (Folder 3)
      - March 26-31, conference, Department of Elementary School Principals, National Education Association, St. Louis, Missouri (Folder 4)
      - April 24-27, convention, National School Boards Association, Chicago, Illinois (Folder 5)
      - May 6, conference, Preventive Psychiatry Research Project, Iowa City, Iowa (Folder 6)
      - June, convention, National Education Association, Los Angeles, California (Folder 7)
      - July 11, workshop, Secondary Education, Los Angeles County Board of Education, Los Angeles, California (Folder 8)
      - July 17-18, panel, University of Nebraska Summer Sessions Clinic, University of Nebraska Teachers College, Lincoln, Nebraska (Folder 9)
      - July 20-30, conference, International Association of Universities (sponsored by the Ford Foundation), Villa Serbelloni, Bellagio, Italy (Folder 10)
      - September 18-20, workshop, State Federation of District Boards of Education, Atlantic City, New Jersey (Folder 11)
      - September 22, conference, New Jersey School Superintendents Association (Folder 12)
      - November 30-December 3, conference, National Conference on Exchange of Persons, San Francisco, California (Folder 13)
      - December----see SUBJECT FILE, Houghton Mifflin Company, Spelling textbook project, promotional materials, Texas campaign
      - December 10-11, conference, "Programmed Teaching and the Educational Process," Thomas Alva Edison Foundation and the Grolier Society, Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, Palo Alto, California (Folder 14)
    - 1961
      - General (Folder 15)
      - January 16, meeting, Elementary Education Council, Burbank Unified School District, Burbank, California (Folder 16)
      - January 17-18, meeting, Los Angeles County Teachers' Institute, Hermosa Beach, San Gabriel, Rosemead, and La Canada, California (Folder 17)
      - January 28-30, conference, "Man and Civilization: Control of the Mind," University of California Medical Center, San Francisco, California (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - February 3-4, conference, "Comparative Education: A Crucial Factor in International Affairs," Comparative Education Association, School of Education, University of California- Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California (Folder 2)
      - February 17, consultant, Denver Public Schools, Denver, Colorado (Folder 3)
      - February 17, seminar, Elementary Principals Association, Denver Public Schools, Denver, Colorado (Folder 4)
      - February 27, convention, American Assocation of School Administrators, San Francisco Regional, San Francisco, California (Folder 5)
      - March 5-6, advisory panel, study of the use and distribution of recorded televised instruction, University of Nebraska, Lincoln, Nebraska (Folder 6)
      - March 13, conference, Instructional Leadership, Sacramento County Schools, Sacramento, California (Folder 7)
      - March 22-?, convention, Department of Elementary School Principals, National Education Association, Atlantic City, New Jersey (Folder 8)
      - March 24, Midwest Program on Airborne Television Instruction, Purdue University, Lafayette, Indiana9March (Folder 9)
      - April 11, meeting, San Ramon Valley Union High School District teachers, Danville, California (Folder 10)
      - April 12, conference, "The Social Studies Challenge to the Curriculum Worker," Hobergs, California (Folder 11)
      - May 5, Wisconsin Elementary School Principals' Association, La Crosse, Wisconsin (Folder 12)
      - May 14-20, Taipei-Tokyo trip (Folder 13)
      - June 15-17, seminar, Project on the Instructional Program of the Public Schools, National Education Association, Washington, D.C. (Folder 14)
      - July 10-21, workshop, Los Angeles County Division of Elementary Education, Los Angeles, California (cancelled) (Folder 15)
      - July 24-29, Cubberley Conference at Stanford University (Folder 16)
      - October 19, meeting, San Mateo County Principals Association, San Mateo, California (Folder 17)
      - November 12-16, Land-Grant Centennial Convocation, Kansas City, Missouri (cancelled) (Folder 18)
      - November 16-19, conference, "The Nature of Knowledge: Implications for the Education of Teachers," University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee School of Education, Milwaukee, Wisconsin (Folder 19)
      - November 23-25--see SUBJECT FILE, National Council for the Social Studies, meetings
      - December 11-12, seminar, United States Public Health Service, State University of Iowa, Iowa City, Iowa (cancelled) (Folder 20)
      - December 26-30, meeting, American Association for the Advancement of Science, Denver, Colorado (cancelled) (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - 1962
      - General (Folder 2)
      - January 4, meetings, Los Angeles County Teachers Institute, Alhambra and South Whittier, California (Folder 3)
      - February 18-21, meeting, American Education Research Association, Atlantic City, New Jersey (Folder 4)
      - February 18-21, convention, American Assocation of School Administrators, Atlantic City, New Jersey (Folder 5)
      - March 1-8, conference, Association for Supervision and Curriculum Development, National Education Association, Las Vegas, Nevada (Folder 6)
      - March 2-3, meeting, Professors of Curriculum, Las Vegas, Nevada (Folder 7)
      - March 24-28, meeting, Department of Elementary School Principals, National Education Association, Detroit, Michigan (Folder 8)
      - June 5, conference, Education Research Council of Greater Cleveland, Cleveland, Ohio (Folder 9)
      - July, conference, Atlantic Institute, Bellagio, Italy (Folder 10)
      - July 5, convention, American Overseas Educationators Organization, Inc., Denver, Colorado (Folder 11)
      - July 5, meeting, Project on Instruction, National Education Association, Denver, Colorado (Folder 12)
      - July 11-12, conference, "America's Emerging Role in Overseas Education," Syracuse University, Syracuse, New York (Folder 13)
      - July 30-April 1, speaking engagement, Peace Corps Philippines VII Training Program, San Jose State College, San Jose, California (Folder 14)
      - August 31, workshop, "Focus on the Future," Naches, Selah and Yakima Public Schools, Washington (Folder 15)
      - October 1-5, speaking engagements and consulting, Teachers' Institute, County of Los Angeles, California
        - General (Folder 16)
        - October 1, meeting, Arcadia Unified School District, Arcadia, California (Folder 17)
        - October 2, meeting, Whittier School District, Whittier, California (Folder 18)
        - October 3, meeting, Excelsior School District, Escelsior, California (Folder 19)
        - October 4, meeting, Inglewood Unified School District, Inglewood, California (Folder 20)
        - October 5, meeting, San Bernardino County Schools, San Bernardino, California (Folder 21)
    - 1963
      - General (Folder 22)
      - February 11, speaking engagement, Shoreline Curriculum In-Service, Shoreline Schools, Shoreline, California (Folder 23)
      - February 14, convention, American Educational Research Association, Chicago, Illinois (Folder 24)
      - February 15-16--see SUBJECT FILE, Houghton Mifflin Company, Spelling textbook project, correspondence, 1963, February 15-16
      - February 16-20, convention, American Assocation of School Administrators, Atlantic City, New Jersey (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - March 10-14, convention, Association for Supervision and Curriculum Development, National Education Association, St. Louis, Missouri (Folder 2)
      - April 3, convention, Department of Elementary School Principals, National Education Association, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma (Folder 3)
      - May 3-5, conference, World Affairs Council, San Francisco, California (Folder 4)
      - June, monitoring, Editorial Board, Phi Delta Kappan, Bloomington, Indiana (Folder 5)
      - July 16-18, conference, "The Social Studies: Curriculum Proposals for the Future," School of Education, Stanford University, Stanford, California (Folder 6)
      - September 4, speaking engagement, "Professional Growth Day," San Diego County Department of Education, San Diego, California (Folder 7)
      - September 4, speaking engagement, Escondido Union School District, Esondido, California (Folder 8)
      - September 29-October 2, conference, American Institute of Biological Sciences, Princeton, New Jersey (Folder 9)
      - October 2-5, conference, "Needed Research in the Teaching of the Social Studies," Maxwell Graduate School of Citizenship and Public Affairs, Syracuse University, Syracuse, New York (Folder 10)
      - October 9-10, meeting, Social Science Education Consortium Council, Perdue University, Lafayette, Indiana (Folder 11)
      - October 11, presentation, Teachers' Institute, Bellevue Public Schools, Bellevue, Washington (Folder 12)
      - October 28-29, meeting, Environment Review Panel, Cooperative Research Program, Office of Education, United States Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, Washington, D.C. (Folder 13)
      - November 25-27, conference, "Designs for Research in the Teaching of English," National Council of Teachers of English, University of California, San Francisco, California (Folder 14)
      - December 6, meeting, San Diego Department of Education, San Diego, California (Folder 15)
      - December 10, conference, Cross National Conference on Childhood and Adolescence, University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois (Folder 16)
      - December 13, conference, Ontario Curriculum Institute, Toronto, Canada (Folder 17)
      - December 22-27, conference, International Conference for the Advancement of Education Research, Faculty of Education, Chulalongkorn University, and Education Society of Thailand, Bangkok, Thailand (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - 1964
      - General (Folder 2)
      - January 31, speaking engagement, Visiting International Scholars and Teachers Association, Stanford, California (Folder 3)
      - February 5, panel, Public Forum, "The Changing World Scene and its Implications for American Education," Pi Lambda Theta, Escondido School, Stanford, California (Folder 4)
      - February 12-15, conference, Fifth Conference on International Education, Institute of International Education, New York, New York (Folder 5)
      - February 15-17, convention, American Association of School Administrators, Atlantic City, New Jersey (Folder 6)
      - February 19-22, conference, National Society of College Teachers of Education, Chicago, Illinois (Folder 7)
      - March 23-25, conference, California State Department of Education and California Elementary School Administrators Association, Fresno, California (Folder 8)
      - March 24-28, discussion, Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, Paris, France (Folder 9)
      - April 15, speaking engagement, Utah State Advisory Committee for Social Studies, Salt Lake City, Utah (Folder 10)
      - April 21-23, colloquium, "Educational Strategies for Newly Developing Countries," Pennsylvania State University, University Park, Pennsylvania (Folder 11)
      - April 27, panel, United States Office of Education, Washington, D.C. (Folder 12)
      - June 8, meeting, Committee on Educational Planning, School of Education, Syracuse University, Syracuse, New York (Folder 13)
      - June 9, seminar, "Major Research Needs in Educational Planning," International Institute for Educational Planning, Bellagio, Italy (not attended) (Folder 14)
      - August 16-22, "School for Executives," American Association of Colleges for Teacher Education, Aneonta, New York (Folder 15)
      - September 2-3, speaking engagement, Scott, Foresman Summer Institute, Chicago, Illinois (Folder 16)
      - September 7-11, conference, "The African University and National Educational Development," Afro-Anglo-American Program in Teacher Education, and Institute for Education in Africa, Teachers College, Columbia University, Lake Mohonk, New York (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
      - September 24-25, conference, "Education and the Modernizing of Nations," Commission of International Education of the American Council on Education, and Wayne State University, Detroit, Michigan (Folder 3)
      - September 27-30, conference, "Learning, Remembering, and Forgetting," The New York Academy of Sciences Interdisciplinary Communications Program, Princeton, New Jersey (Folder 4)
      - October 11-14, meetings, Kalamazoo Public Schools, Kalamazoo, Michigan (Folder 5)
      - October 21-22, meeting, Advisory Committee, Division of Education, W.K. Kellogg Foundation, Battle Creek, Michigan (Folder 6)
      - November 6-7, conference, California Advisory Council on Educational Research, San Francisco, California (Folder 7)
      - November 26-28, meeting, National Council for the Social Studies, St. Louis, Missouri (Folder 8)
      - November 26-28, meeting, National Council of Teachers of English, Cleveland, Ohio (Folder 9)
    - 1965
      - General
      - January-March (Folder 10)
      - April-December (Folder 11)
      - January 13-14, meeting, Advisory Committee on Private Enterprise in Foreign Aid, Washington, D.C. (Folder 12)
      - January 28, meeting, faculty committee, Northwestern University, Evanston, Illinois (Folder 13)
      - January 29-31, seminar,Agricultural Development Council, American Universities Research Program, Stanford University, Stanford, California (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - March 7-8, seminar, Agricultural Development Council, American Universities Research Program, University of Hawaii, Honolulu, Hawaii (Folder 2)
      - March 11-13, conference, "Dynamics of Development," Society for International Development, Washington, D.C. (Folder 3)
      - March 19, speaking engagement, World Understanding Week, Rotary International, Honolulu, Hawaii (Folder 4)
      - April 24-28, meeting, National Education Association, Department of Pulbic Schools
        - Papers presented (Folder 5)
        - Planning session correspondence (Folder 6)
        - Program (Folder 7)
        - Speech by P. Hanna, April 26 (Folder 8)
      - April 26, meeting, National Education Association, Department of Elementary School Principals (Folder 9)
      - April 29, consulting, Detroit Public Schools, Detroit, Michigan (Folder 10)
      - May 14, speaking engagement, Stanford Alumni Club, Honolulu, Hawaii (Folder 11)
      - June 2-6, meetings, Manila and Quezon City, Philippines
        - General (Folder 12)
        - June 2-3, seminar, "New Approaches to Educational Administration," Phillipine School of Graduate Studies, Manila, Philippines (Folder 13)
        - June 3, dinner, Philippine Depart- ment of Education, Manila, Philippines (Folder 14)
        - June 4-5, conference, Philippine Association for Curriculum De- velopment, Manila, Philippines (Folder 15)
        - June 5, convocation, Graduate College of Education, University of the Philippines, Quezon City, Philippines (Folder 16)
      - June 6, forum, Philippine Association for Graduate Education, Quezon City, Philippines (Folder 17)
      - July 9, speaking engagement, National Finals, Outstanding Young Educator Program, U.S. Junior Chamber of Commerce and World Book Encyclopedia, Washington, D.C. (Folder 18)
      - August 5-10, meeting, Committee on Education and Human Resource Development, Dartmouth College, Hanover, New Hampshire (cancelled) (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - October 3-6, conference, "Learning, Remembering, and Forgetting," The New York Academy of Sciences Interdisciplinary Communications Program, Princeton, New Jersey (cancelled) (Folder 2)
      - October 8, conference, Oregon Elementary School Principals Association, Portland, Oregon (cancelled) (Folder 3)
      - October 20-21, seminar, Pilot Projects in International Understanding, American Association of Colleges for Teacher Education, Hamline University, St. Paul, Minnesota (cancelled) (Folder 4)
      - October 23, symposium, Teacher Education, Delta Chapter, Phi Delta Kappa, School of Education, Stanford University, Stanford, California (Folder 5)
      - November 16-19, conference, United States National Commission for UNESCO, Kansas City, Missouri (cancelled) (Folder 6)
      - November 26, convention, National Council for the Social Studies, Miami Beach, Florida (cancelled) (Folder 7)
    - 1966
      - General (Folder 8)
      - January 20, meeting, Delta Chapter, Phi Delta Kappa, School of Education, Stanford University, Stanford, California (Folder 9)
      - February 15, convention, American Association of School Administrators, Atlantic City, New Jersey (Folder 10)
      - February 17-19--see SUBJECT FILE, American Educational Research Association, meetings
      - February 25-28, conference, Anglo- American Conference on New Educational Techniques in Developing Countries, Ditchley Foundation, Ditchley Park, Enstone, Oxfordshire, England (Folder 11)
      - March 11-12, meeting, Professors of Curriculum, San Francisco, California (Folder 12)
      - March 19-23, convention, Department of Elementary School Principals, National Education Association, Portland, Oregon (Folder 13)
      - April 7-9, workshop, "The Schools Look at a Changing Society," North Star Borough School District, Fairbanks, Alaska (Folder 14)
      - May 14, conference, Stanford University Alumni Association, Stanford, California (Folder 15)
      - June 16-17, conference, National Foreign Policy Conference for Educators, United States Department of State, Washington, D.C. (Folder 16)
      - July 18-19, workshop, Training Educational Planning Personnel, International Institute for Educational Planning, Paris, France (Folder 17)
      - October 9-12, conference, "Learning, Remembering, and Forgetting," The New York Academy of Sciences Interdisciplinary Communications Program, Pacific Palisades, California (Folder 18)
      - October 28, meeting, Metropolitan Educational Study Council, Department of Education, San Diego County, San Diego, California (Folder 19)
      - November, panel discussions, Stanford Center for Research and Development in Teaching, School of Education, Stanford University, Stanford, California (Folder 20)
      - December 9-10, retreat, School of Education faculty, Stanford University, Asilomar, California (Folder 21)
      - December 14, speaking engagement, national sales meeting, Addison Wesley Publishing Company, Palo Alto, California (Folder 22)
      - December 21, seminar, Resource Strategy, Ralph Smith (Stanford University faculty member), Stanford, California (Folder 23)
    - 1967
      - General (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Engagements refused (Folder 2)
      - Trip contact sheets (Folder 3)
      - February 9, speaking engagement, Upsilon Chapter, Pi Lambda Theta, Palo Alto, California (Folder 4)
      - February 11-15, convention, American Association of School Administrators, Atlantic City, New Jersey (Folder 5)
      - February 24-26, meeting, California Association of Teachers of English, Los Angeles, California (Folder 6)
      - March 20-22, conference, Ontario Institute for Studies in Education, Toronto, Ontario, Canada (Folder 7)
      - May 2, meeting, Physician's Assistant Development Project, Santa Clara County, San Jose, California (Folder 8)
      - July 7, conference, International Education Act of 1966, Stanford, California (Folder 9)
      - July 17-28, workshop, International Institute for Educational Planning, Paris, France (Folder 10)
      - September 17-22, conference, Third International Curriculum Conference, St. Catherine's College, Oxford, England (Folder 11-13)
      - October 5-9, conference, International Conference on the World Crisis in Education, Williamsburg, Virginia (Folder 14)
      - October 15-19, symposim, International Symposium on the Frontiers of Learning, Lake Como, Italy (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - October 27-29, discussions, Phi Delta Kappa International Relations Commission, Chicago, Illinois (did not attend) (Folder 2)
      - October-November, trip to Africa
        - General (Folder 3)
        - October 19-24, Kenya (Folder 4)
        - October 24-29, Malawi (Folder 5)
        - October 29, South Africa (Folder 6)
        - October 30-November 2, Lesotho (Folder 7)
        - November 2-9--see Kenya
        - November 9, Uganda (Folder 7A)
        - November 9-14, Ethiopia (Folder 8)
      - November-December
        - Trip to Africa (Folder 9)
        - Trip to South and Southeast Asia
          - Afghanistan (Folder 10)
          - India and Iran (Folder 11)
          - Singapore (Folder 12)
          - Malaysia (Folder 12A)
          - Singapore (Folder 13)
          - Thailand (Folder 14)
      - December 20-22, trip to Hawaii (Folder 15)
    - 1968
      - General (Folder 16)
      - Engagements refused (Folder 17)
      - January 12-13, lecturer, Jennings Foundation, Kent State University, Kent, Ohio (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - January 17-19--see SUBJECT FILE, Peace Corps-University of Hawaii Study Committee, meetings
      - February 28-2, conference, Achieving Reading Excellence, Regional Reading Center, Bothell, Washington (Folder 2)
      - March 8-9, conference, International Education, Phi Delta Kappa, and College of Education, Florida State University, Tallahassee, Florida (Folder 3)
      - June 20-21, conference, Department of State (Folder 4)
      - July 22-26--see SUBJECT FILE, Houghton Mifflin Company, Spelling textbook project, correspondence, 1968, June 20
      - August 9-12, seminar, "The Role of Higher Education in National Development in Asia," Seoul, Korea
        - General (Folder 5)
        - Accounting for Bannigan (Folder 6)
        - Asia Foundation, Korea (Folder 7)
        - Bibliographies, research pieces, etc. (Folder 8)
        - Calendar (Folder 9)
        - Clippings (Folder 10)
        - Correspondence
          - General (Folder 11)
          - Bannigan (Folder 12)
          - Mun, Hui Suk (Folder 13)
        - Participants (Folder 14)
        - Proceedings, papers, reports (Folder 15-17)